mobileballot.com 2012-03-10

# None

Last Updated: March 8th, 2009

Please review our _Terms of Service_ which also govern your visit to our sites(s) to understand our practices.

**Mobile Ballot Privacy Policy**

Welcome to the MobileBallot.com ("Mobile Ballot") Web site run by Issues Based Media ("Issues Based Media," "we," "us," or "our"). Issues Based Media is committed to respecting the privacy rights and concerns of all users of our MobileBallot.com Web site (the "Site"). As such, we have established and implemented this Privacy Policy to inform visitors to this Site how we use and protect the information we collect at this Site.

Our business changes constantly and our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service change also. We may e-mail, text or in other ways provide periodic reminders of but you should check our Web site frequently to see recent changes. Your continued use of the Site following any changes to this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such changes.

If you have any questions regarding this information or our privacy practices, please see the section entitled "Questions? Contact Us" at the end of this privacy statement. This privacy statement is effective as of 03/08/2010.

**What information does Issues Based Media collect?**

We collect certain types of information and ask for personal information in certain circumstances, such as when you participate in a survey, take a poll, sign a petition, set up an account, or it is necessary to participate, for example, in a contest, petition, sweepstakes promotion, survey or other activity. The following sections describe what type of information we collect, when we collect it and how we use it.

**Information you give us**

We receive and store any information you enter on our Web site or give us in any other way. For example you provide information when you search for a issue, a quiz or a product: place an order through Mobile Ballot or one of our associated sites; purchase an item, participate in a poll, provide information in your online account: communicate with us by phone, e-mail, SMS/MMS or otherwise; complete any questionnaire, survey, petition or entry form; or employ any of our notification services or engage in any of our services.

In order to use certain functionality of Mobile Ballot, you will have to submit certain personal information. When you register and create an account, we may require you to provide us such personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") as your name, telephone number, mobile telephone number (if you have a mobile phone), e-mail address and home address and/or zip code and voter registration information. When setting up an account, should a program offer a payment method of participation, you may also be asked to submit the type of payment method you would prefer to use if you choose the payment method, including your mobile phone account (if you have one) or your credit card. If you do not provide such information when you set up your account, you will have to provide it at the point of purchase or at other points as prompted by the Mobile Ballot web site. Upon activating an account, you may be required to select a user name and password, or other identifier. Your user name and password (or other identifier) will be used so you can securely access and maintain your account, or at times, if any, securely participate, for example, in a promotion, engage in the Mobile Ballot services or engage in an activity. In addition we may collect information associated with your usage participation and submissions to our Web site and features. We might collect any and all information associated with your practices and actions. We may also collect demographic information that you provide to us, such as your zip code or income level. We use your demographic information to tailor the Site to you and for internal purposes. 

**Automatic Information**

In the process of operating our Web site(s) and interacting with you we may now or in the future automatically collect and analyze a variety of information. This information may include but is not limited to, the internet protocol (IP) address, login; e-mail address password; computer and connection setting browser plug-in types and versions operating system and platform; purchase and participation history; products you viewed or searched for; and the ways you used to contact us.

We also may use browser data such as cookies or software tools to measure and collect session information. Cookies are small bits of electronic information that a Web site can transfer to a visitor's hard drive to help tailor and keep records of his or her visit to the site. The use of cookies is standard on the Internet and many Web sites use them. Cookies allow Web site operators to better customize visits to the site to the visitor's individual preferences. For example, by setting a cookie you may not have to log in using a user name or password more than once, thereby saving time. We currently save user name and password information in cookies, however, we do not receive or record any personal information in the cookies we use. Although most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, you can usually change your browser to prevent that or to notify you when you are sent a cookie. Even without accepting a cookie, you can still access Mobile Ballot but may not be able to participate in activities that require cookies for participation. However, to access your account, you may still have to reenter your user name and password each time you visit the Site.

**Information from Other Sources**

We may receive information associated with your account from other sources including 3rd party advertisers, affiliated companies, 3rd party billing providers, and credit card processors. Mobile Ballot may also allow third-party to advertise on or link to our site(s) You can find out more about the information collection and use practices of these other parties by examining their associated policies.   

**Gifts and Contests**

We may offer contests gift offers to our account holders from time to time. To enter each particular contest, a user must submit their name, email address, mailing address, relevant phone numbers, and comply with The Terms of Service and the terms and conditions which may apply specifically to the offering. We may aggregate certain information from our users when they participate in contests, games or sweepstakes so we may better understand what types of contests, gifts appeal to our customers. We will use such information in the aggregate and may connect such information to personally identifiable information.

**Customer Service**

We provide customer service support through e-mail or telephony. In order to provide customer support, we will ask for your e-mail address and phone number. We only use information received from customer support requests, including e-mail addresses, mobile phone numbers and user names, for customer support services and we do not transfer or share this information with any third parties, except third parties who may help us administer such customer support, if any.

**How do we use the information you provide us?**

As stated above, we use your personal information such as your name, address, and mailing address for customer service, to administer contests, gifts and sweepstakes, notify if you've won a prize in a contest or gift offering or sweepstakes, to send you a prize or gift, to provide you with information that pertains to your place of residence or that you may request, send you newsletters and to customize your experience on the Site.

We may use your credit card number or mobile phone account for billing purposes when we charge you (and you have agreed to be charged) for any purchases you may make, including but not limited to fees for participation in a promotional activity. By entering a contest or gift offering or by making a purchase on the Site, you consent to our providing your financial information to our service providers and to such third parties as we determine is necessary to process your transactions. These third parties may include the credit card companies and banking institutions used to process the transaction. We also will use your e-mail address and user name and/or password to send you email updates and messages about contests, gift offerings or sweepstakes in which you have chosen to participate, or about future programs, issues, activities, offers, promotions, surveys, petitions and Site news in which we think you would have an interest, or to contact you when we provide customer support.

In addition, we may also use your e-mail address to send you information on updates to the Mobile Ballot features and services which we may make available from time to time. To opt out of receiving these e-mails, please see the section below titled "How do you opt out?" However, you should be aware that if you opt out of receiving a-mails concerning updates and messages about contests, in which you have chosen to participate, you may no longer be able to effectively participate in them. Please note that changes to your preferences may not be effective immediately.

We may also provide information about our visitors and accountholders to outside parties from time to time. For further details, please see the section below titled, "Does Mobile Ballot disclose the information it collects to outside parties?"

We may use the information we collect to tailor your experience on Mobile Ballot features and services by displaying content according to your interests and preferences, providing a faster method for you to access your account and submit information to us and allowing us to contact you, if necessary, such as, but not limited to, when a new issue, petition, survey or service is available, redeem prizes or gifts from a sweepstakes or contest.

We may use the information we collect to provide current and future customers with new products and services. In efforts to provide better, more tailored and higher valued services, we may market to customers existing, new or upgraded offerings, products and services.

**How does Mobile Ballot protect customer information?**

We implement a variety of security measures to ensure the security of your personal information on our systems. User personal information contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of employees who have special access rights to such systems. Any credit card information you supply us is transmitted and protected via Secure Socket Layer technology ("SSL") and then stored into our databases to be accessed only as stated above.

**Does Mobile Ballot disclose the information it collects from its visitors to outside parties?**

When you participate on the Mobile Ballot website, participate in petitions, surveys, contests, newsletters, gift offerings or premium offers, the Personal information you disclose for these and similar activities may be shared with third parties, such as those who may administer and fulfill the activity for us and shipping companies who may deliver a gift, prize or premium. Purchases through our Site, if offered, may require disclosure of your Personal information your credit card information and information about the name and address of the person receiving the purchases. The credit card information may be subject to verification by the issuing credit card company or other company. Shipping information will be shared with the shipping company. Sales and shipping records will also be generated and maintained. Unless you give us permission at the time we collect such information, however, this information will not be used for any purpose except the fulfillment, and record keeping of the transaction.

We may share your personal information with 3rd party organizations to independently market and /or communicate with you. In addition, we may temporarily populate a third party advertising offer with your personal information to make any ordering process more seamless and efficient for you..Should you respond to a particular offer from our business partners or advertisers that may be offered on our Site, we may also use your personal information to provide a report to our advertisers or business partners that tells them who responded to a particular offer. Further if you accept an offer contained in, for example, an email, we may provide the advertiser or business partner with the personal information necessary to fulfill that offer to you.

Your personal information may be shared with those persons or entities that administer our Web site, with other companies and Web sites we own or operate for our behalf and/or with third parties for their internal purposes. We may share, sell or trade personal information with third parties who may use such information to directly market offers to you. If you are a resident of California, and do not want your personal information shared with these third parties for marketing purposes, please let us know via e-mail at privacy@MobileBallot.com

If as a result of a business transition, information will be used for a purpose different from that stated or implied at the time of collection users will be given a choice consistent with our notification of changes section.

Should you change your mind about the information you've provided to us, should you no longer wish to receive information from us, or should your information change, we have provided a way for you to correct, update or remove the personal data you gave us. For further details please see the section below titled, "How do you change the information we have for you?"

In the event Issues Based Media goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, account holders' information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Visitors and account holders will be notified via prominent notice on the Site for 30 days prior to a change of ownership or control of information of users held by us. Notwithstanding any other term of this privacy statement, we may release any personal information we obtain or collect when we believe its release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our Site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety. Should you win a gift, prize in a contest or sweepstakes, that information together with the personal information required, will be disclosed as required by law.

**Individuals under 13 years of age**

This Site is not intended for children under 13 years of age. Therefore, pursuant to the provisions of the 1998 Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"), our policy is to refuse individuals under the age of 13 years of age to submit information to the Site or to install and/or use the Mobile Ballot features we therefore do not knowingly collect personal information from individuals under the age of 13 years of age. If you are under 13 years of age, you are not permitted to use the Mobile Ballot Features or services. If you are over 13 years of age, your obligations, conduct and inclusion in the Mobile Ballot services and offerings is subject to The Terms of Services

**How do you opt out?**

In order to opt out of receiving e-mail notifications and updates, please access the “ “ [need] area of the Site and you may select the "Do not send me e-mail updates and notifications" option.

**How do you change the information we have for you?**

To update, modify or delete the information that we have on file for your account, simply send an email to [_info@MobileBallot.com_](mailto:info@MobileBallot.com) then submit your modification as necessary or ask to be contacted directly. We will comply with your requests as reasonably as we can. Please note that we require some personal information for billing purposes. If you wish to delete your name, mobile telephone number, e-mail address or mailing address and zip code you will be required to terminate your account.

**Third party links and co-brand relationships**

In an attempt to provide increased value to our visitors, we may choose various third party Web sites to link to, and/or frame within the Site. We also participate in co-branding and other relationships to offer e-commerce and other services and features to our visitors and account holders. However, even if the third party is affiliated with us, we have no control over these linked sites, each of which has separate privacy and data collection practices independent of us. Data collected by our co-brand partners or third party Web sites (even if offered on or through our site) may not be received by us. As such, we have no responsibility or liability for these independent policies or actions, and are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any such Web sites. These linked sites are only for your convenience and you therefore access them at your own risk. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of the Mobile Ballot features and the links placed upon each of them and therefore request any feedback on not only the Mobile Ballot features, but for sites each links to as well (including if a specific link does not work).

Further, any linking with any other Web site is neither an endorsement of that site nor any of the products or services which may be offered on that site.

**Surveys**

From time-to-time, we request information from users via surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as your email address), and demographic information (such as interests or age level). Survey information may be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of the Mobile Ballotfeatures and services. We may also use information from these surveys to better distribute market and provide products and services to new and existing users.

**California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, permits our Web site users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, should you be a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to: Issues Based Media at Issue Based Media Inc., 1221 Brickell Avenue, No. 900, Miami, Florida 33131.

**Notification of changes**

By visiting the Site or using the Services, you consent to the collection and use of information by us as set forth in this privacy statement. If we decide to change our privacy statement, we will post those changes within this page so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

**Questions?**

Contact us if you have any questions about our privacy practices or your dealings with the MOBILE BALLOT Features, please do not hesitate to contact _[info@MobileBallot.com](mailto:info@MobileBallot.com)_

Please also read the Terms of Service establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of the Site, the Services and other Mobile Ballot services and applications.
